Hi, my name is Kiran Vajapey.
I'm a senior HCI developer at Figure Eight.
Today I'm going to talk to you about Machine Learning and Automated ML.
I'm very excited to talk to you about this lesson. So let's dive in.
In this lesson, we're going to dive deeper into
Machine Learning and understand the concepts behind ML models.
You will see how we train models to carry out complex tasks by
observing historical data and tuning parameters to do this with high accuracy.
As a product manager looking to develop AI products,
it is important to understand the mechanics of Machine Learning.
Model architecture, training data and model evaluation are all
key elements of ML and are instrumental in successful AI product management.
When using AI and products,
there are numerous uncertainties that can alter the course of
development and by understanding the core concepts,
we can stay ahead of the unknowns and plan development accordingly.
The concepts in this lesson will cover various aspects of Machine Learning,
some more technical than others.
If at any point you find yourself lost in the technical weeds, don't worry.
These topics are meant to give you a peek under the hood of
ML and get familiar with some of the components.
When building AI products,
you are very likely to interact with experts in the field,
and knowing some of the lingo will allow you to
be more effective when managing these products.
So let's get started.