In this quiz, we wanted you to identify what type of
trading data is best used for creating a voice assistant for a hotel concierge service.
When we look at the options,
we can immediately start to eliminate a few of them.
If we look at option B,
we see that it's calling for 10,000 images of hotel concierge activities.
We can immediately remove this because in order to train a voice assistant,
image data is unlikely to be of any use.
Similarly, we can eliminate option D because that is calling for
video data which is essentially a series of images connected together.
Then, we have options A and C.
Option A, while it is collecting the correct type of data,
we see that it only is collecting two hours of audio data which is unlikely
to capture all of the types of scenarios that you may encounter in a hotel concierge.
That leaves us with option C.
Ten hours of audio data of
concierge desk conversation and 50 hours of
audio data from the most common guest-concierge interactions.
As you can see this will capture a fair amount
of real-world data as well as diverse data from
different locations which will provide us
with a sufficient dataset to train our voice assistant.