There we are. In machine learning,
the training data is key to building robust AI.
We rely on the data to give the machine
all the insights needed to process the real-world data.
If we remain aware of the types of data the model will encounter in the wild,
then we can tailor our training data to encompass as many cases as possible.
While it may not be feasible to cover every corner case,
over time we can monitor the performance of
the model and understand where the model performance is weak,
and update the model as necessary.
In the next section,
we'll go over exactly how to evaluate your models,
to understand where the model is performing well and where the model is lacking.
This will allow us to ensure,
that the models we build will be successful when put into production.