In this section, we will discuss specific methods to measure model performance.
Having clear performance metrics will allow us to understand where
the model is performing well, and where we need to pay more attention.
I want to give a disclaimer that we'll be doing some math in this section,
but don't worry if that's not your strong suit.
We will be stepping through examples to make it as clear as possible.
When measuring model performance,
we want to have sensible metrics that indicate how well the model is performing.
This should encompass the model's ability to predict each of
the train classes and give us insight into any biases that may exist on the model.
By having these clear metrics,
we can get a good idea of how the model will perform when deployed into production,
which will ultimately guide the performance of the product and its impact in the market.
In order to measure a model's performance,
we use data similar to how we use data to train the model.
From the total set of labeled data,
we generally use 80 percent for training data,
the other 20 percent,
for testing the model.
It is important to note that the training data
and test data should both be as balanced as possible.
Similar to the issues we saw in training the model,
having unbalanced data in the test data may
skew our perspective of the model's performance.
For example, if the test set is made up of a majority of a single class,
then we will not have a robust enough test cases to determine
whether the model is performing adequately across all classes.
In addition to test data,
validation data is sometimes added as another split.
The validation data is used during training to help inform
updates to model parameters and is different from the test data
because the test data is never seen by the model until after
the training is complete to simulate a new set of data that the model has never seen.
This way, we can evaluate how the model would perform on data
that is completely different than the data used while training.
The way we evaluate these models is to start with our labeled test data.
We feed this data through the network which produces each of the labeled data points.
By comparing the predicted labels and the actual labels,
we start to get an idea of where the model's performing
well and where the model needs improvement.
We need a measure of performance.
We could count the number of correct and incorrect predictions.
However, we want to understand the performance of
each class which requires more than a simple count of incorrect verse correct.
Two common measures we use when evaluating a model are precision and recall.
Both of these will measure the model such that we can
understand how the model performs for an individual class,
as well as how it performs across classes.
Looking at this graphic on the right,
we see the model's predictions inside the circle.
The left half of the graphic represents the ground truth in the data,
and the right half of the graphic represents negative or non-existent data.
To give an example,
if we had three images of cats and only two of them were identified as cats,
we would see the two correctly predicted cats on the left half of
the inner circle and the missing cat on the left half of the outer square,
representing a false negative prediction.
Conversely, if we misclassified a dog as a cat,
that would fall on the right half of the inner circle as a false positive.
Modeled precision answers the question of when the model makes a prediction,
how likely is that prediction to be correct?
In order to calculate the precision,
we will take the number of true positives aka the number
of correct predictions and divide it by the total number of predictions.
This will tell us what percent of all the predictions were correct.
We start with predicted labels for each of the data classes.
We will first calculate the precision for each class.
For cats, we take the number of
correctly predicted cats and divide that by the total number of cat predictions.
In this case, we have one correctly predicted cat and two cat predictions,
one for the actual cat,
and one for the misclassified gerbil.
This gives us a precision of 0.5.
Similarly, we do the same calculation for dog and gerbil classes.
In the case of gerbils where zero gerbil predictions were made,
we simply assign a zero position.
This is another reason why we want
enough test data so that we will have at least one prediction for each class.
Now, to find the models overall precision,
we take the average of all the precisions.
Now, we can say we have a model precision of 0.5 or 50 percent.
Next, we'll calculate the model recall.
Model recall answers the question of how good is a model
at identifying actual occurrences of objects in the data.
This will give us an understanding of whether or
not the model can recognize these objects.
We calculate the recall by taking the number of
correct predictions and divide that by the number of actual occurrences.
This will tell us what percent of the real occurrences were recalled by the model.
Again, we start with the models predictions of each data point.
We go ahead and calculate the recall for each of the models classes.
This time, for cats,
we take the number of correctly predicted cats
and divide that by the total number of real cats.
In this case, there's one correctly predicted cat,
as well as one actual cat.
This gives us a recall of one.
We then do the same calculations for
all other classes and take the average of all the recall values.
In this case, our overall model recall is 66 percent.
As you can see, both the precision and recall of the gerbil class are very poor,
which indicates we may need to improve the model for this class.
Additionally, while the recall for the cat class is one,
we saw poor precision of 0.5,
which means that the model may be biased towards
this class causing erroneous cat predictions.
A third measure that is commonly used is called the F1-Score.
The F1-Score combines the precision and
recall to produce an overall performance measure of the model.
The F1-Score ranges from zero to one,
with one being perfect precision in recall.
Generally, an F1-Score above 0.75 or 0.8 will be considered decent.
However, it will depend on the intended application and how
critical the performance of the model is to the success of the product.
In our case, we saw an F1-Score of 0.57.
This indicates to us that the model definitely needs
more training cycles in order to improve the overall performance.
Finally, we can plot a confusion matrix to understand which are
our problem classes and get an insight into how we should update our model.
The Confusion Matrix is a grid which shows
all the predicted labels relative to all the true labels.
When looking at this chart,
the values across a row should add up to a 100 percent,
while the values in the columns have no limitations.
This chart shows that 100 percent of
the true dogs were classified 100 percent of the time in the dog category.
Similarly, 100 percent of the cats were
classified 100 percent of the time in the cat category.
The gerbils on the other hand,
reclassified 100 percent of the time in the cat category as well.
This shows us that the cat category is getting
an unbalanced number of predictions while the gerbil category is not getting enough.
This should give us some insight into where we can improve
our training data to increase the model's accuracy.