That sums up our model evaluation.
We use test data to calculate the precision and recall for each class on the model,
as well as an overall model Precision and Recall.
We use the metrics to calculate an F1 score,
which gives us an overall performance measure of the model,
taking into account correctly and incorrectly predicted examples for all classes.
We also plotted the predictions on
a confusion matrix to get into where model biases may occur,
and which classes we should focus on their future trading cycles.
Next, we will talk about transfer learning and automated ML.
These are two facets of machine learning that have made
the development of ML models more accessible to developers,
as well as to individuals who may not have had
as much engineering or scientific background