Now, we move on to transfer learning and automated ML.
These are two disciplines within
machine learning that have helped push the ML field further,
making machine learning more accessible to a larger audience.
Transfer learning is when we use the knowledge from an already trained network,
with a similar use case which is stored in
the architecture of the network as well as the weights,
and adapt that to a new use case.
Generally that requires different classes.
This allows us to develop models with significantly less data
because the neural network can retain
the knowledge it learned from previous training data,
sometimes millions of data points,
and slightly tunes parameter to fit our needs.
Automated ML takes this one step further by allowing us to build
relatively robust and scalable models without much Machine Learning experience.
In the following project,
you will build the Machine Learning model through
an automated ML service provider to get
some real hands on experience with model-building.
In order to do this,
we take the first N layers of the pre-trained network.
The number N is generally all except the last or last few layers,
depending on how deep the original network is.
Then, we copy these layers into a new model.
These copied layers will retain
the same architecture as well as the same weights and activation functions.
Then, we will attach new layers to the end to replace the old ones.
Here, you can see the number of
output nodes is actually different between the two models.
This is because in the first model we are supporting four classes.
While in the new model we only required two.
Once we have the new network,
we go ahead and retrain it to tune the last layers of
the network that will give us the supported classes we're looking for.
In this example, we copy the weights from the first N layers into the second model,
and only retrain the last layer of the new model.
This is specifically called transfer learning,
where the weights on the earlier layers do not change.
Another version of this is called fine tuning,
where you use the same process but also retrain the earlier layers.
Each model has its pros and cons,
and will be largely dependent on the training data that is available.
But at a high level,
the idea behind transfer learning and fine tuning is that we can leverage knowledge
that was previously learned and make
slight modifications to accomplish in different task.
This will generally reduce the amount of trained data
necessary to accomplish a particular accuracy,
which makes creating models using
transfer learning and fine tuning much quicker and cheaper.
Today, we see a lot of these pre-trained models available for free online.
By using these pre-trained models,
some of which have been trained on millions of data points,
we take advantage of previous training cycles and require
much less data to adjust or tune the model to identify the desired classes.