Coming to automated machine learning.
This is where Cloud service providers such as Google Cloud and
IBM Watson offer ML model creation services.
The way these services work are that you bring your labeled data to
the platform and they will automatically train and tune the model to fit your case.
This allows you to easily build and test
an ML model with little additional work to actually serve the model.
One major benefit along with this platform will come enterprise support.
This combination offers an overall solution with significantly less complexity.
An added benefit of using these services is that
many of them will conduct neural architecture search on the back-end.
This will automatically select the optimal architecture for
your model by fitting various components together and assessing their accuracy.
All of this will be handled by the service provider and is often
how they're able to effectively scale their ML solutions.