That's the end of this section.
We saw how transfer learning can be used to
leverage knowledge from other models to speed up
the creation of new ones by copying a portion of
the first model and tuning it for a specific need.
People often post pre-trained models online,
which had been trained on thousands or millions of data points and
often serve as a great starting point for model development.
Automated ML is another segment of machine learning where
service providers will offer tools to create ML models.
Generally, these platforms will have a limited set of use cases.
If there's a need for more complex models then a custom model may be the way to go.