That brings our lesson to a close.
Hopefully now, you have a better understanding of
some of the components that make up machine learning.
Machine learning models are defined by
their architecture and the training data used to train them.
In order to use machine learning models in production,
we want to thoroughly evaluate the performance,
so we are aware of the model and how it's likely to perform when deployed.
In machine learning, there are certain tools such as transfer learning and automated
ML that we can use as aids to help us build models faster.
In the following project,
you'll get first-hand experience at creating your own ML models
and getting intuition for how the data impacts the outcome of each model.