Here are the concepts we'll cover in this lesson.
We will start with a look at the actual models used in
machine learning and understand the components that make up this technology.
Next, we will talk about the training data which someone called the currency of ML.
Training data serves as the examples from which the machine will learn.
Subsequently, after training any model,
we need to understand the model's performance,
and we'll follow with the discussion of model evaluation and what key metrics we
want to measure to understand how our model is likely to perform in production.
Finally, we will talk about transfer learning.
A core concept in modern-day machine learning that allows
us to bootstrap models and achieve robust performance relatively quickly,
as well as automated ML which has made machine learning more accessible to
individuals looking to develop performance AI without requiring a PhD in data science.
But that said, let's dive into the first section.