To begin, let's go back to our previous example,
of determining whether or not we should go to a co-workers party?
This is a network with a single mode.
We had three inputs,
along with a weight for each input,
to show which ones were most important.
Indeed we found that adding these weights is critical,
because they allow us to adjust the likelihood of a certain decision based on inputs.
In this example, it meant that we absolutely cannot attend the party
if we are not free, which is very sensible.
The other factor that allowed us to come to this conclusion,
was the decision threshold.
Had we said a decision threshold of three instead of seven,
then indeed there would be a case,
when we would choose to attend the party even if we aren't free.
Now, it is clear in this example that we want a threshold above four,
to handle the case that we aren't free.
However, you can imagine if we're looking at
pixels in an image or large documents of text,
that this decision threshold may not be so easy to determine.
This is where we see the application of activation functions.
Activation functions, are functions that we can use as decision boundaries,
to tell us whether or not to send a signal to subsequent layers in the network.
Furthermore, activation functions allow us to pass a range of
values to the following layer instead of a strict zero or one for yes or no.
As I mentioned, activation functions serve
as individual nodes decision boundary,
that will determine the signal that is passed to the subsequent layer.
An ideal activation function,
would return a range of values which will allow us to scale
the nodes output rather than having a binary yes or no decision.
Starting with these activation functions
we will piece together the different parameters,
that are tuned when training a neural network.
To illustrate this binary decision boundary,
a basic threshold is in essence a step function.
This means that until we pass our threshold we do not pass a signal,
i.e we have a zero or no decision,
and once we reached the threshold,
we immediately jumped to one,
i.e an absolute yes.
Now in this case of attending a party a yes or no decision is fairly obvious.
However, when executing a complex tasks such as transcribing a document,
we want to allow for some uncertainty so
that even if the machines transcription is not perfect,
we can still get a decent output after which
we can have a human make minor adjustments if necessary.
Just like shipping products,
allowing machines to make decisions,
means we have to allow them to be imperfect.
This means that we need a better decision boundary
that will give us room for error.
One such function is called a sigmoid function.
Using a sigmoid function we receive an output with a range of zero to one.
And this provides a continuous decision boundary
where each node in the network acts as a sort of knob.
As the network is trained these knobs are adjusted
to produce the optimal output.
So the way to think about this is that when training the network
we will adjust parameters on each node in the network.
To other common functions are the rayleigh function
and the leaky rayleigh function.
These simplify the activation function to
a linear equation which allows for faster and less complex training.
The general idea, is that we don't pay as much attention to
the negative inputs which reduces the number of nodes that are activated,
thereby simplifying the network.
These are the most commonly used activation functions,
and have been shown to generally performed
the best among activation functions.
So going back to our example,
we now want to update our model with one of
these dynamic activation functions to
allow the model to provide more insightful decisions.
We start by substituting the decision threshold
with one of the activation functions.
Here we'll go with the sigmoid,
since we want a go or no go decision.
Now we can use placeholders for the weights
which will be set when the model is trained.
Now we have a node that is completely configurable,
instead of having hard set weights and a single threshold,
the training process will now set these weights based on the labeled data.
Given an input, you will provide the machine with the desired output,
via your training labels in the training data.
The machine will end incrementally update those weight parameters,
to best optimize the model for all input output pairs.
This is how the model learns from the training data,
and why the training data is absolutely critical to the model creation process.
The actual method for updating the weights is called Back Propagation.
You don't need to go into the details,
but just know that it is an algorithm used to
automatically update those weights on the inputs in each node.
Now one more thing I want you to know is that the nodes
shown here is a specific type of node called the perceptron.
In machine learning, we actually have many different types of nodes,
that each of which has their own pros and cons,
and are used for various applications.
To give you an idea that node we saw previously is used
in what's commonly known as a Multi-layer Perceptron which is
a specific type of neural network.The idea is that you have a bunch of
these perceptrons connected in layers without outputs of
a previous layer feeding inputs to a subsequent layer.
Another type of network is known as a Convolutional Neural Network which is
widely used in computer vision tasks such
as image classification and object detection.
On the bottom here you see a LSTM or Long-Short Term Memory Network,
which is commonly used in natural language tasks such as speech recognition.
Again, you don't need to know the specifics
of each of these networks but know that there are
different types of nodes and networks that are specialized
for various use cases.