So in this quiz we wanted to identify
which of these statements are true about activation functions.
Going through the list,
we see the option A discusses thresholds.
We saw that using thresholds are not the best options,
because they act as step functions,
which simply return a zero or one instead of a continuous value.
Looking at the next option we do actually like sigmoids,
because they return a continuous range between zero and
one allowing a range of decisions rather than simply yes or no.
Looking at C and D,
we see that these are both discussing ReLU functions.
However, in option C,
it says that they are linear from negative infinity to infinity which is incorrect.
ReLU functions in fact have different slopes below zero and above zero.
This is why we select B and D as the correct options.