That's a high level overview of modeling and machine learning.
We learn that Neural Networks are the basis for much of ML we see today.
These networks consist of nodes that are linked together through inputs and outputs with
activation functions that determine whether or not a node will forward information.
The most common activation functions are the Sigmoid and the Rayleigh functions,
because they produce a continuous output allowing for
a range of values pass from one node to another.
Weights on the inputs of each node are tuned and ultimately define the behavior
of data flowing through the network by throttling each inputs impact on the node.
Additionally, there are different types of nodes and
networks that are specialized for specific use cases.