Now, we're going to talk about training data.
Training data is the currency of machine learning
and is the basis of learning component in ML.
A good way to think about neural networks in the context of
training data is to imagine a young child that has never seen a car.
After being told what a car is and interacting with
different types of vehicles such as buses and trucks,
the child will eventually learn what a car is and can identify them in the future.
Similarly, a machine learns by looking at many examples of a given object and
will eventually learn that a pattern and data can
be associated with a specific classification.
Now, unlike children, machines are much more difficult to train and
require special care and attention to ensure they're learning the correct concepts.
In machine learning, the data is key to model performance and outcomes.
If you want a model to learn a specific concept,
it must be clearly represented in the data
in order for the machine to learn it for the future.
This means that for example,
if you want a machine to learn to detect animal sounds and audio,
you must provide the machine with examples
of all the types of animals you would like it to learn.
Furthermore, if the data used to train the models inaccurate for example,
you have humans making these animal noises,
then it is unlikely to work on real
animal sounds as it has only learned simulated human sounds.
With that said, let's go through an example of training a model to
see how the model behaves given different types of training data.