Here, we want to train a model that can determine the type of pet in an image.
To start, we have batches of labeled data that are fed into the Network for training.
Once a network is trained,
it retains all the knowledge learned from the example images.
In this case, there are two classes of animals that are
represented in the model; cat and dog.
Now, when the model sees a new image that is not previously seen,
it is able to predict the animal contained in the image.
As we can see, this works great with images of dogs.
Similarly, if we feed in this image here,
the model is able to determine that this is a cat.
In these examples, we can see that if the model is given unknown data,
as long as that data similar to the training data,
then it is able to infer the content of that data.
In this case, cats and dogs.
Now, if we feed this image into the data,
this proves problematic because the pet contained in
this model is not one that is represented in the training data.
Therefore, a cute gerbil was assigned the label of
cat since the model only has knowledge of cats and dogs.
In order to remedy this situation,
we can train the model on a third class of gerbil images.
Now, the model is aware of the gerbil class of pets.
When we feed this image into the model,
we now indeed get the correctly predicted label of gerbil.
Now, we can see that if the model is not given a particular type of data,
it will never be able to infer on other types of that data.
Only after being trained on a given type or class of data,
will the model begin to make predictions of that type.