So some key points to note are when training a model,
you must train it with all types of data that the model is likely to
encounter in the future in order to build a robust model.
Adding diversity to your data is also important because similar to
how the model did not know a gerbil class until it was shown the correct data,
if the model only encounters dogs in the snow,
then it is very unlikely to identify a dog pictured in a field of grass.
Like I said earlier,
models require proper care and attention to be robust and performance.
To illustrate this in another example,
let's imagine you want to build a model to recognize shoes.
Like in the previous example,
we start with some training data.
In this case, three different images of shoes.
In order to get a diverse set of data,
we've even included a sketch of shoes.
Now, once we have trained the model,
we put the model into the wild and try to run on some real-world data.
As you probably guessed,
this is not going to work.
The training data only represented a very specific type of shoes, clogs.
While these may prove to be great footwear from Northern Europe,
they do not represent all the types of shoes we see today.
Instead, let's train our model with a more diverse set of footwear.
Here, we have included boots,
sneakers, dress shoes and even flip-flops.
Now, when we see a real-world example,
the model will be able to correctly identify the shoes.
So looking back at these examples,
we should understand that the data used to train the machine learning model is
absolutely key to producing a robust and usable model in the real world.
Depending on the intended usage of the model,
we want to make sure that we are using diverse enough data which means understanding
all the potential scenarios that the model is likely to
encounter and accommodating for those in the training data.
Additionally, we want to reduce the amount of noisy data as much as
possible and ensure that the labels we are providing to the machine are accurate.
Next, I want to walk you through some common issues we see in
training data that can significantly impact the outcomes of our models.
First off is the distribution of training data.
In this chart, you can see an example of unbalanced training data.
Of the four classes, two of them,
cat and dog have significantly more training data than bird or snake.
This may be due to a number of different factors,
including the fact that snakes are simply less common pets than cats or dogs.
In cases of unbalanced data,
the model will learn significantly more about cats and dogs than
other classes and we'll tend to bias towards those classes when running in the wild.
In order to prevent this outcome,
we either want to collect more training data for the classes that are
lacking or reduce the amount of training data for those that have too much.
While more training data will often lead to a better model,
balancing the data is as important if not more to produce an unbiased model.
The second case is similar to the example with shoes we saw earlier.
This is where the training examples are different than the real-world examples,
even when they technically fall into the same class.
To put this in an example,
here you can see two audio recordings.
The recording on the top was collected in a recording studio,
while the one on the bottom was collected from a mobile device.
As you may see, the audio collected from the mobile device has
a great deal of noise as the cases real life situations.
If we were to train the model,
only on studio audio,
our model would fail miserably at detecting audio collected from mobile devices.
This is an example where we want to be aware of what the real-world data will look like,
so we can collect appropriate data.
Next, we have the issue of mislabeled data.
While you may think it is very difficult to mix
up a dog and a horse when labeling images,
you can imagine in this example where we are parsing entities out of text, in this case,
it may be quite difficult to properly labeled the data as it can
be unclear where any particular entities should be classified.
In this case, we want to be very careful when assigning labels to
our training data and ensure that when we are collecting the data,
either manually or through a large platform provider,
the labels that are returned are accurately classified as expected.
Finally, we have the quantity of training data used to train our models.
This is actually much more fuzzy as the amount of data
required will vary widely based on a number of factors,
including the datatype, complexity of the data.
Again, you want to make sure that you're thinking
about what the real-world data will look like,
and the model and model architecture itself.
While there is no clear-cut rule as to how much data will be needed,
we generally want to start with a few 100 examples of
each target class and then scale up
the amount of training data until we reach a desired accuracy.