Welcome to AI for product managers.
In this nano-degree, you'll learn about how to build products that leverage AI.
I'm Alyssa Simpson Rohwerger.
Thanks so much for joining me for this lesson.
I've had the privilege to be doing product management for
close to 10 years building data intensive products.
The last four years of which I've been using machine learning technology.
I'm currently VP of product at Figure Eight, an apping company.
Figure Eight combines human and machine intelligence to provide
high-quality annotated training data that powers
the world's most sophisticated and innovative machine-learning and business solutions.
Previously I was a customer at IBM Watson as director of
product management for a portfolio of
different machine learning products that included computer vision,
speech, machine translation, sentiment analysis.
Let's get started. What we're going to cover in today's lesson is an overview of AI.
How that's different from machine-learning.
Cover some terms like neural network and deep learning as
well as a little bit around what the current state of the art is in AI.
I'm really excited about AI technology because generally speaking,
I believe it has the potential to rapidly change our world for the better,
helping people improve outcomes across industries.
Some of this I get to see every single day and it's really cool.
Everything from improving outcomes for patients,
to being able to scale customer service and have people be far less frustrated,
to reducing drought and water usage here in California.