On the other end of the spectrum,
we have unsupervised learning.
Unsupervised learning finds patterns in data.
Clustering is a good example here of unsupervised learning,
where the original data is all gray and
unsupervised learning can cluster the data into three different sections.
There are very few business applications of this,
but there's quite a few examples in
the media of unsupervised learning particularly in game play.
An unsupervised learning use case that may actually be deployed in
a business or production environment is around an e-commerce website.
So if you have a static or fairly static e-commerce website
and you're asking the question
what is a common customer journey or
path through the website that results in a high conversion,
you can look at the data.
Using an unsupervised learning technique,
cluster the customer journey into
those different patterns or paths that customers take
to actually purchase something.
So it could be that people go to your product page,
and then they drill down into different collections or featured products.
Then, they add something to their cart and they go linearly
through this order summary,
and out to shipping.
Or, they may go to your homepage and have
a totally separate journey around managing their account.
These can be different clusters of
using unsupervised techniques that you can bubble these up
and learn about them.