Another category of unsupervised learning is around reinforcement learning,
which is an area of machine-learning concerned with
how machine learning agents
ought to take action in an environment so as to maximize a specific outcome.
So you may be familiar with
an example such as the chat bar that was put up
by Microsoft a couple years ago,
where it was an agent that was learning about
and having conversations with the public.
It didn't go so well because what happened was,
the public actually trained it in a situation that was less than
favorable and ended
up sort of learning a lot racists and unsavory techniques.
So reinforcement learning is really, really powerful.
When it actually takes those actions from an environment in that reward,
and it's interpreted and fed back into the agent to
learn about the environment and continuously make decisions.
If you don't have a human in the loop in reinforcement learning
to deploy the production,
it can be really scary and often
unwise to deploy that without some sort of manual intervention.
An example of reinforcement learning
here that I used a lot to explain it's like a two-year-old.
So when you are teaching a two-year-old about different animals,
and you're like,
hey this is a cat and this is a dog and this is a cow,
and they may have a picture book in front of them.
Then you'd get them out to an actual barnyard and they see a cow
for the first time,
they may look at you quizzically and be like cow,
and you're going to as the parents reinforce that,
you're going to say, "Yeah, honey that's a cow."
That reinforces it for that child,
and they learn what a cow is.