So we're going to switch gears a little bit
and talk about current state of the art AI,
and what's actually being used in reality.
So right now, AI can do specific,
narrow tasks pretty well that learn from large volumes of unstructured data.
These can sometimes be referred to as
first generation AI applications that are referring
to as artificial narrow intelligence.
These systems are all over the place in our daily lives.
They enable Facebook to recognize our faces and images, they tag users,
it's what Siri uses to understand your voice and act accordingly,
or enable Google to find the search results you're looking for.
But each of those tasks is narrow and discrete.
So there's certain things that AI can do really
well right now or better than even the best human.
There's achieve superhuman performance in mostly game play.
Again, limited to narrow and specific tasks.
Similarly to humans, AI can be really good at classifying images,
as we mentioned, handwriting recognitions or facial recognitions.
However, AI is really bad when you start
asking if to do anything outside of what it's been trained on.
So if you took an incredibly efficient image classification model and you said,
"Instead of just classifying inside or outside,
can you actually put a caption and describe what's going on
in this image of children in the forests playing with ball?"
It would probably fall apart.
AI is pretty bad at doing more complex tasks
such as anything that requires contextual knowledge or explainability.
Machine translation gets really stuck or
as I was mentioned before, general speech recognition.
It can do it really well and narrow,
and specific environmental settings often in limited cases better than humans.
But when you're trying to generalize something,
AI is very brittle.
Self-driving cars, good example.
If there were no humans on the road,
there'll be self-driving cars all over the place today.
But we haven't quite bridged the gap here dealing
with nuanced situations and complex unpredictable situations,
which humans are all the time of self-driving cars or even translation.
As you can see, if you're translating something from English to French,
this program fell into the trap.
Not realizing that as any human reader would that I was describing a couple.
Stressing that for each item,
he had, she had a similar one.
For example, the deep learning engine that used the word SA
for both his car and her car.
So you can't tell anything about either car owners gender.
The human-translated French version is
quite different from the machine-translated version.
Sebastian Thrun, as we are at the brink of being able to take AI,
have it, look over our shoulders,
and then it will make us maybe 10 or 50 times
as effective as these repetitive things.