So let's go into a couple of different examples of AI technology actually applied.
Facial recognition is an easy example that comes up all the time.
It's now at near human or better than human level performance
depending on the context.
Anyone who uses Facebook can tell you that lots of AI
is used to recognize faces,
and it can sometimes go overboard into
an interaction that maybe make people feel uncomfortable.
Computers can easily recognize individual people along with emotion,
and even micro-expressions that you might not be
aware of that you're having yourself.
Another example that I use all the time when I'm traveling on
business is automatic text recognition.
So if you're traveling on business,
you might take pictures of your receipts to automate your expense reporting.
What the computer vision is actually doing is finding
where the amount is on the receipt.
Transcribing that amount, transcribing the date and
any other relevant information of
the receipt to help facilitate and make expense reporting way easier.
Before I started using this technology,
it would take me a couple hours at the end of
the week to categorize all of my receipts and do my expenses.
Now I don't even set aside time anymore because on
the go I simply take a picture and it automatically works for me.
Even more granularly, this is an example where computer vision
technology using semantic segmentation can take
every single pixel in an image and assign it to a particular object,
way more granular than just bounding boxes.
You can say this pixel is belonging to this object which is identified as a person,
car, or a road.
Imagenet is a prestigious computer vision contests
where teams compete to recognize objects and images.
Shown here is the top five error rate,
and over the last ten years you can see that computer vision has gotten
way better and actually getting better than humans over classifying images.
You can see the difference in older techniques,
and newer deep learning techniques which are driving the improvements here.
From an application perspective,
you may use a computer vision in a social media use case.
This is really common with big brands.
They want to understand ''hey,
where is my brand being talked about online?''
You can't simply do keyword matching and search
for you Udacity and how often that comes up on Twitter.
You might need to understand,
hey this is a picture of my logo or my brand that is being talked about,
and take the corresponding texts and do sentiment analysis and
natural language processing to understand whether or
not someone saying something nice about this class,
or something perhaps a little more constructive.
Similarly, speech recognition has had the same set of
step function improvements which have led to products
like Amazon echo or Siri.
I argue with my Amazon echo all the time.
My husband has installed,
I think we have three or four echoes in our house.
However, unfortunately Alexa doesn't recognize me all the time.
It's because speech recognition is not quite there in
terms of human level computation in real-world environments.
If you've ever been in a noisy restaurant,
you can understand some of these difficulties.
So if you're in a noisy place,
what your brain actually does is it tunes out the ambient noise
around you and it tunes in to what the person across
the table is actually saying to you,
and this is something that is really difficult to teach a computer
to do the same thing.
There's been drastic improvements in the last five years,
but speech recognition is still really tricky.
If you perhaps speak English as not your first language
or you have an accent from the South or New York,
or perhaps a different dialect or speaking style where
the system hasn't had as much exposure and hasn't been trained on that,
it can make the error rates really high.
Another example, there's all different types of
audio recognition not just transcribing speech.
But it could also be around recognizing mechanical
failures by listening to engines.
As you can see, here's what's working or what's not working.
Natural language processing is yet another area
that has made huge advances in the last five years.
It doesn't demo quite as nicely as computer vision,
but it's just as interesting.
Techniques such as filtering out hate speech in
social media platforms or perhaps when you're reading the New York Times,
and you're looking through the comments,
and there's no foul words there,
or it's making a recommendation based on what stock to buy based on
what companies are being talked about in positive
or negative sentiments online.
Here you can see as an example of textile,
which is an AI technology that gives advice on the quality of your writing,
and how good it is as you're writing it.
I wish I had this in high school.