So 50 years ago,
AI was used to describe transformational technologies like a calculator.
Today, it might be sort of hard pressed to find
anyone who thinks a calculator is a great example of AI.
However, what's most important to take away is that this
continues to change as the technology changes.
So machine learning is a term that applies to algorithms
which can learn from data.
Typically speaking today that often references
supervised learning techniques where humans actually massage the data,
design different sort of representations or features of that data,
and train a model.
More recently deep learning is a subset of
machine learning in which there's multilayered of neural networks
that learned from very,
very large sets of data to predict outcomes from unstructured inputs.
Generally speaking, AI integrates perception so understanding the world,
predicting, reasoning, and decision-making around getting
to a particular outcome.
So what do people mean when they refer to "AI'?
The term AI is aspirational,
a moving target based on those capabilities that humans possess
but machines do not.
These days when people say AI,
they often mean the most advanced machine-learning techniques
that are available today,
that may be deep learning but in a few weeks from now
or a few months from now that may be referencing something totally different.