So I want to shift gears a little bit and talk about industry applications of AI,
and what I'm seeing actual businesses and customers use this every day.
So Andrew Ng says that AI is the new electricity.
It's something I really subscribed to.
A hundred years ago we didn't have access to electricity,
and it transformed every major industry,
and it was impossible to really predict ahead of
time how that transformation what's going to happen,
or what the outcomes were going to be, right?
So in agriculture suddenly you had refrigeration techniques,
so you could move food around.
In communication, suddenly you had the telegraph,
so you we're no longer using mail, then the Internet.
Manufacturing ray, you created the electric motor,
it really just transformed every single industry.
Similarly there are applications across every industry in AI.
A study by PWC projects that by 2030,
there's going to be $15.7 trillion added to the global economy,
and a lot of that's going to come from
labor productivity improvements, and product enhancements.
A couple sectors that I see today having huge strides in AI,
very commonly is e-commerce.
Often this comes down to pricing and promotions,
customer service management such as helping to reduce the time that
it may take to get a response from a customer service department such as password reset,
or can you help me refine my serial number?
In consumer goods, a lot of innovation going
into supply chain management or demand forecasting.
Being able to route goods and services to
where customers are most likely to purchase them.
Even in finance around marketing and sales,
how do I know when perhaps someone is likely to get married or have a baby.
I may want to sell them different insurance,
or manage risks differently with that particular customer.