So an example of a customer of ours,
that is Blue River technologies.
They were recently purchased by John Deere for over $300 million,
and they operated a technology that was put on tractors
to help distinguish between,
what is a weed and what is a plant.
So what they were doing is using computer vision to identify, "Hey,
this is a weed and it's outlined in red here,
and this is a plant that we're actually interested in
growing a crop which you can see outlined in green."
What that ended up resulting in from a business application perspective,
is that the tractor was able to only spray herbicides
on the weeds and not the crops.
Which resulted in a 90 percent reduction in actual herbicide use,
and a lot less going into the water table.
Which is not only great for the environment,
but also reduces costs significantly.
It would've been impossible for folks to hire enough people and
staff that's in a way where you could selectively
spray herbicide in such a granular and narrower way.
It was just untenable.
But using AI technology,
you can do this at scale which is really cool.