So now we're going to take a little bit of
a deeper dive into machine learning specifically.
So what is machine learning?
Machine learning is a branch of artificial intelligence,
as simply put by Tom Mitchell,
Professor and Former Chair of the Machine-Learning Department
at Carnegie Mellon.
Computer algorithms that improve automatically through experience,
pretty simple.
We're going to go over three major sections of machine-learning
and different techniques.
Supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and reinforcement learning.
Supervised learning uses pre-labeled data to train a model to
predict new outcomes for information that hasn't been exposed to before.
Unsupervised learning uses non-labeled data and self
organizes to predict patterns or outcomes such as clustering or associations.
Reinforcement learning is giving feedback to an algorithm when
it does something right or wrong based on a discrete outcome,
this can either be in real time or offline.