Supervised learning is what most of machine learning and production
today is actually using and it's mapping inputs to a particular output.
So in this case,
the input is a picture of a mountain and the output is, mountain.
Very close to a 100 percent of actual production machine learning,
business technology is actually using supervised learning.
So in a simple way supervised learning,
input image, output label.
Person or not person, person.
This is an example of classification which is categorizing
unstructured data into particular categories or a class.
You could also have multiple categories.
For example in this case,
instead of just two classes of person or not person you could
have three categories which is person, plant, or neither.
Another version of supervised learning is regression.
So the main difference between classification and
regression is that the output variable in
a regression is numerical or continuous
while classification it is categorical or discrete.
So in this case, you have input data which is homes
and some information about the house, how big it was,
how many bedrooms or bathrooms,
and the output is a label which is the price for that home and what it sold for,
and so you can use this to do regression.
Most supervised learning use cases fall into these types of use cases.
So machine translation, we talked about audio transcription,
or event detection, sentiment analysis,
optical character recognition, natural language processing.
There's all different types of supervised learning
that are deploying these techniques.