In this lesson, we are going to review how to actually build
successful products that use machine learning technology at scale.
Here are several examples of ways real companies are using AI today
to realize value.
In this lesson, we're going to talk about developing
AI application in a business setting.
Some common things are facial recognition, retail inventory management,
e-commerce search relevance, a lot of use cases
in customer support automation.
Yesterday, we talked about agricultural automation.
There's all types of use cases with data categorization and classification,
and lots of ways to manufacturer efficiency and
quality control which are some of my personal favorite use cases.
Of course, things like OCR, autonomous vehicles,
sentiment analysis is really popular in social media and marketing use cases.