So another example using search is LinkedIn here.
So LinkedIn has used machine learning technology to classify companies,
improving their job recommendations.
They measure success here by increasing the initial in mail response rates.
In this case, they were able to improve them by over 45 percent.
Another way they measure success is the number
of two-way conversation started.
Here, they were actually able to double that.
So I know I get lots of job recommendations from LinkedIn,
and it looks like they've really improved
the outcomes based on implementing natural language processing,
and machine learning techniques.