A question I get often is,
do you even need AI?
Not all projects are well-suited for AI or machine-learning.
Let's talk a little bit about what makes a project well-suited
for using this technology.
Some key considerations are:
do you have an impactful business problem that warrants solving?
Is this problem big enough and important enough?
That's a high enough priority that you can
quantify the business value clearly and simply.
Does this problem have a huge volume of
associated data that the machine-learning technology can actually learn from?
Is that data well-organized and is it complete?
How much data do you actually solve?
The data is the most critical piece of this problem here.
So let's focus a little bit more on this.
Just because you have a lot of data,
doesn't necessarily mean it's the right data.
Does the dataset match the problem that you're trying to solve for?
Is that dataset complete?
Is that annotated correctly for the machine-learning team?
Does it have unwanted bias in it or anything else that
shouldn't be in that dataset that's likely to have a negative business outcome?
Spending a lot of time actually looking through your dataset and
samples of it in detail is absolutely critical as the product manager.
You can't just relegate this task to the machine learning or data science test.