A question folks often ask is,
do you need traditional Machine Learning approach
or a Deep Learning approach?
For that, it really depends on the problem you're solving,
and the data available to solve that problem.
This is best left to the data science person on your team to make
this decision about what types of models or approaches
to use to solve that problem.
It's best to make sure that you as the product manager,
are clearly communicating what success means for the model.
Let's take for example,
a use case in manufacturing.
But this is one of my favorite clients that I've worked with.
They were actually trying to put the correct label on
pieces of chicken coming off a conveyor belt in a manufacturing setting.
The question that they were trying to answer was is this abreast
or a leg or a wing?
In this situation, you may not need very much data because
there's a fixed camera.
There's only three different categories that you're trying
to classify the chicken into,
and the training data is very representative of the real world scenario.
Say, you may only need maybe 5,000 images to get
a relatively solid confidence level, and accuracy.
Alternatively, if you had a different problem,
if you wanted to classify every single item in a grocery store,
visually say take the Amazon go stores that the super different problem.
Say there's a 100,000 different products in the stores with different orientations,
different lighting conditions, perhaps different languages even.
You'll need millions of examples of imagery to successfully
achieve a business outcome.
Deep Learning requires perhaps thousands or millions
of rows to achieve acceptable performance,
and millions to meet or exceed human performance.
You can also short-circuit this often by starting
with the base model that's trained,
and just customize it for your specific needs.
Many platforms offer this such as Google,
Auto ML, or IBM Watson,
or Amazon sage maker.
Going back to the theme of learning,
production systems actually learn.
You need to think about your data pipeline once you deploy to production,
and make sure that you're getting this step right.
If you train your chicken classification model with
the wrong data or perhaps you were misinformed by the factory,
and addition to wings breasts, and legs,
there's also a fourth category of chicken thighs.
How is your system going to learn over time about data it hasn't seen before,
or it has low confidence in.
Setting up a data pipeline for training not just once but
continuously is super critical for the product long-term success.
In this case here,
the model will look at this chicken that it hasn't seen before chicken thighs,
and it's going to be not confident.
It's a best practice to incorporate real humans into
this training pipeline so that he can set the non-confident data to a human,
and the human can look at and be like oh that's a chicken thigh,
and then feed that information back to your model.
Typically this is where versioning comes in or continuous learning,
and your model can be updated or improved based on new information,
and the next time it sees chicken bites,
it's going to have a higher confidence level than before.