So things to remember.
Start with the business value,
break it down into small and specific component of the process
that you want to improve.
Get real with the data,
use production data, not academic data,
not data that you found under the covers,
or under your bed, or under the mattress.
You want to use production data to ensure that
the training data matches the reality of the real world deployment.
Learning is key to value.
Learning from new data ensures consistent improvement over time.
Let's take another example of a good candidate for machine learning.
Take a customer support use case.
Costs on average about four dollars per chat conversation and
about nine dollars for
phone conversation when you're engaging with the customer support team.
Often, in tier one support,
there's a lot of repetitive content.
It's frustrating for the customer service department,
to deal with the same conversations over and over and over again,
and it's difficult to scale up or down to
predict how much volume will come in over a given time frame.
It can also be a huge cost center for the business.
But, look at ways to add machine learning technology to improve this.
Let's take for example Autodesk,
which makes architecture and other business software.
They had exactly this problem.
What they did, was turn to natural language processing
to automate as much as possible.
They started small.
They started with a narrow business problem,
which was just password reset which represented
a meaningful percentage of inquiries that they
got in their customer support center,
and they taught a chatbot to recognize,
when the user's question was about a password reset,
and they got the chatbot to help the customer automatically,
without involving a customer support representative.
When the natural language processing system recognized
that the customer inquiry was not about password reset,
the chat was routed to a live support system for resolution.
Rinse and repeat over time,
they were able to add additional use cases,
up to about 60 different types of use cases and ended up supporting a
100,000 increase a day automatically using natural language processing.
Excuse me, a month.
The business outcome here was that on average,
they cut the resolution time from before about a day and a half, to 5.4 minutes.
That's a lot happier customers.
As you can see here, it's often a mix.
There is no magic solution here when deploying machine learning technology.
It's a mix of keeping humans in the loop, in reality,
and gradually expanding the use case overtime.