It's one thing to build on my laptop,
it's a very different thing to deploy it to hundreds of thousands or millions of users.
In reality, cross-functional teams are critical for driving business outcomes.
You need a team that is made up of folks who cut across disciplines.
You can also have multiple teams running in parallel.
You'll need folks from product and design, engineers,
DevOps, QA, data engineering, data science.
From an HR perspective,
they may not all report into one team or a general manager.
They may report in functionally,
but in order to have a successful product launch,
you need folks representative of all of these different types of skill sets.