Now, we'll discuss a couple of key roles.
So obviously starting with the product owner.
This person owns the business case,
they bridge from stakeholders to the team,
they maximize the product value and they ensure
that the team builds the right product that's going to solve a business score.
Often overlooked, I think one of the most key positions on a team,
making sure that the team really focuses on the user,
is a designer The designer will own the Human-Computer Interaction Design.
Take Amazon's Alexa's use case.
The design here has really changed over time.
At first, Alexa simply didn't respond or showed
lights flashing when they didn't understand what I was saying.
It was a frustrating experience for me as a consumer.
Often, Alexa guessed wrong what I was trying to say
or she misinterpreted and let me down a path that I didn't want to go down.
Now, when Alexa has low confidence about what I've said,
sometimes Alexa will ask me as the user to clarify
my statement and confirm if it was interpreted correctly.
That's a much better experience for me as a user of the product.
You absolutely need software engineers to actually build the product.
Front-end, back-end expertise who were building this problem infrastructure,
they're problem-solving from a software development perspective
and they're generally bringing things to life.
A newer role is a role that has developed recently called a data engineer.
This person is often taking a model from a machine learning team and getting
the data infrastructure and pipelines setup
to support rapid development in iteration after launch.
Often the state engineers also responsible for
model management or AB testing or validation.
A data scientist will build and select a model,
they'll guide the team and state their research and technology,
they'll structure the problem to actually achieve
the business metrics and we'll use data to answer those business problems.
A Q&A team member will own the quality of the product outcome.
They'll speak the person who's signing off and that product is ready to release.
They'll do scalability testing and functional testing.
A DevOps team ensures the infrastructure and reliability.
They're managing scale and performance.
They're mitigating any security risks and their
ensuring smooth operations between
the machine learning team and the engineering team and
efficiency across the technical teams.