So let's end here with project management,
and getting this actually as a team into production.
So I'm often asked here,
how much time will this take?
The answer is it depends.
No different from normal Scrum and Agile.
I highly recommend Scrum.
This process could take a week, a day,
end to end or could take six months depending on how fast you can learn
and iterate.
I've spent months just tracking down the right dataset to use,
or I've seen teams spent three months doing
feature and hyper-parameter tuning and specification,
or weeks training models.
I've also seen models trained in five minutes using off the shelf products.
Deploying and measuring really depends a lot on
your tooling and your infrastructure that you're using,
or if you're going to build that all from scratch.
Again, it sometimes takes an hour to get stakeholders on
track depending on the size of your organization or it
could take six months in a highly matrix world.
It totally depends.
It's important to use Scrum.
Super normal, no different from normal development processes.
As the team you're doing backlog planning, sprint meeting, backlogs.
A Scrum teams sprint can last anywhere from one to four weeks.
There's lots of great online resources around Scrum and how to run that.
I believe Udacity also has some great courses. So check those out.