To summarize, make sure you start with the business problem.
It's important that you really understand and communicate that as the product manager.
It is your most important job.
You have to communicate that business problem to
stakeholders and everyone else on your team alike.
Make sure that you have the right data,
make sure your team as the right data.
Make sure there's nothing missing from that data,
and make sure that you actually roll up your sleeves and look at that data get
nitty-gritty into the details of it because as a product owner,
it's important that you really understand the nuances of your data set.
It's easily overlooked.
Make sure that you have an interdisciplinary team that you're working with.
That's cross-functional and representative of all the skill sets that
you're going to need to actually get this product into production.
It's not just a data science team,
and make sure that as a team you're working together,
you're learning and you're iterating fast.