This is a typical machine learning training pipeline that
many machine learning teams use to start building products.
They typically start and have a dataset that's available to them,
they may spend some time cleaning or
organizing and jump right into building a model of training it,
validating it, and then straight to deployment.
I see this time and time again.
I spent three years at IBM Watson actually trying to make this stuff work in reality,
and what I found was that you actually need to
start with the business problem not the data.
At Figure Eight, we work with about 200 enterprise clients who were actively
running real production jobs and getting business value out of it.
If they weren't getting business value, they wouldn't pay for it.
Our most successful clients start with the business problem and
one of these steps you could spend months refining,
optimizing, clarifying, and digging into more.
It's about figuring out how to start small and narrow,
and then expanding as you realize the business value.
The business problem is often the hardest part by far,
and it's critical part of what product managers
should focus on and exactly what problem you're solving.
For example, I made this mistake when I first worked
on computer vision which is that we just said, "Oh,
we want to recognize stuff from images and I didn't clarify it any further",
that did not end up being a particularly successful product and market for V1.
It was only later when V2, and V3,
and V4, when I narrow the business problem,
that we wanted to actually build an API for
developers to train and recognize custom visual content that
they cared about in their business when we ended up with
a very successful business application and product that did well.
Let's go through a couple of these steps.
First, again, business problem,
you have to define it,
you need to quantify the value,
you need to identify who those stakeholders are,
what's the priority of this business problem
relative to everything else that you have going on in your business,
and what level of investment are
those stake holders willing to make to solve this problem.
You can spend days, weeks, or months,
just defining the business problem and getting people support.
Once you've done that,
then you can move on to actually the data problem.
You need to figure out. Do you have the right data to solve the business problem?
What's the provenance of that data?
Are there any security issues or PII issues,
you should be thinking of?
What's the coverage of that dataset?
Does it need to be cleaned, or augmented,
or annotated in any way in order to
hand it off successfully to your machine-learning team?
What's your strategy for refreshing the data and having
a pipeline of development of that data over time,
so that your model will continue to stay
fresh to solve the actual business pane at the beginning?
Only then should you move on to model-building.
This is where the machine-learning team typically gets involved,
you can do feature extraction,
tune the hyperparameters, and benchmark against
different datasets and different validators.
Once you've actually built a model that you're happy with from an accuracy perspective,
then you can go and actually deploy it.
I see lots and lots of people stalling here,
which is that they built a model of an ends up
sitting on the shelf and not actually deployed.
You want to make sure you have a clear path as a product manager to deploying that model,
because if the model sitting on the shelf
you're never going to realize your business value.
Setting up ways to AB test perhaps different versions of that model,
or tuning different outcomes and integrating it seamlessly into the business process.
Once you've deployed your model into production,
it's time to actively learn in a production environment need to mitigate unwanted bias,
such as, was your dataset actually complete for the real world like you thought it was?
Making sure that you're refreshing your ground truth,
monitoring for success against not just the accuracy or
an F1 score as often things that a machine-learning team will use to measure success,
but accuracy against solving your business problem.
What kind of versions do you need?
Rinse and repeat.
Again, you could do this entire problem in a day, a week,
or a month depending on your business problem, the size of it,
the availability of the data,
and the team that you're working with to execute.