It's important to start with the problem not the data.
You can imagine it's like trying to pack for a trip
but you don't know the destination.
You'd pack very differently if you were going to Hawaii versus skiing in Aspen.
Starting with the data is like trying to pack
your suitcase when you don't know where you're going or for how long.
You're likely to pack the wrong thing,
forget important items, over pack, under pack.
You certainly could buy things when you get there, sure,
but it'll be more expensive and you might feel a little
silly in Aspen with just your flip-flops at a swimsuit.
The most important part here is to actively learn frequently,
not just once, not quarterly,
not monthly but setting up
a dynamic active learning pipeline which is always benchmarking against
a gold standard and updating that gold standard
dynamically as the nature of the unstructured data changes in reality.
As you can see, the robot here is going to make a decision once it's deployed,
if it's confident, if it's met your threshold,
or if it's not confident.
Typically, you'll need to have human in
the loop process to learn from and give that feedback back to
your model so it can continuously learn and improve
the scope of what it's confident in to improve your business outcomes.