So let's talk a little bit about making a business case.
How do you know what a good problem is for AI?
How do you define that problem,
value it, gets stakeholder buy-in, and investment?
As an example, one of our clients is Adobe.
One of Adobe's flagship offerings is Adobe Stock,
a curated collection of high-quality stock imagery.
The library itself is staggeringly large.
There's over a 120 million photos,
diagrams, videos, and graphics.
There is an additional a 150,000 uploaded every day.
As a product manager for Adobe,
they need to make all of these images findable to
their customers and have a delightful experience.
Let's get in the mindset of a customer of Adobe's.
Typically, their clients are looking for a piece of
specific visual content for perhaps a marketing campaign or a product launch.
They may have an aesthetic perspective in mind and they need to
find that one in a 120 million images like a needle in a haystack.
They couldn't possibly look through all a 120 million.
So Adobe can help them by classifying images into categories,
deploying visual search technology,
recommending images to them,
or suggesting similar images to ones I've seen before to
those clients based on perhaps past image purchases.
The business problem here is find the right image fast for the customer.
This helps you narrow the scope of the problem.
It's unlikely you want your product to address the entire scope of the job.
So in this case,
let's break down that job.
Here, the customer of Adobe needs to find a stock photo for
our marketing collateral which is likely to drive improved conversion and sales.
So what this person actually does and
whether or not they are conscious about all of these different steps,
as a product manager here,
it's important to write them all down and
clarify exactly what each step is trying to accomplish.
So in this case,
this client would gather examples of photos which historically had high conversion.
They also may gather examples of photos which have had lower conversions.
They are going to identify visual criteria that are
consistent with those high converting photos
and inconsistent with the low converting photos.
They may then log onto Adobe Stock photo database.
They're going to generate a search query.
They're going to search for what they're looking for,
and they're probably going to get lots of results.
This is the point where they may apply filters to narrow
those results or perhaps start scrolling through
pages and pages to identify
images with the corresponding visual aesthetic that they're looking for.
They may then narrow it down to a couple options,
evaluate pricing, and eventually purchase the image.
This is the job to get done.
So let's think a little bit about where the user pain is most acute here in this flow.
We're going to take a quiz here.
Which sequential steps could use
machine learning computer vision technology to accomplish this task?
One through three, two through five,
five through eight, or seven through 10.