There is no one right answer in this case.
However, one that would work well would be steps five through eight
which would be creating a visual based search
using machine learning computer vision technology.
Typically, this is called
a visual similarity search and it's deployed frequently on e-commerce websites.
The customer of Adobe could use that image that they gathered in step
one and simply look for visually similar images using machine learning.
The reason this is a good problem for machine learning is that,
one, you have a lot of data,
you have a clear sense of what the job is that needs to get done
and to be accomplished,
and you have a job previously that is tedious and impossible for humans to
do in a realistic time-frame which is searched through a 120 million images.
Another tool that can help understand
the business problem is identifying the AI value and
spending time writing down the details of
what actively needs to get accomplished by that user.
If that could be done by a human or by a machine learning and what
the value is of that narrow and granular or specific activity.
It can help you stack, rank,
and prioritize different opportunities for machine learning.
This also helps you identify what data is needed to accomplish a specific task.
So two examples here,
the activity would be identifying images with
the corresponding visual aesthetic qualities.
Another one could be identifying images with space for Ad copy.
Here's how human would accomplish it versus an AI
and then being really clear on what the value and the outcome is there.