So typically, when you're building an AI product,
you're going to create what's called a project statement.
As a product manager it's really cleared to
communicate to your stakeholders what problem are we solving.
In this case, we are helping marketers find
the right stock images for
marketing collateral in order to improve their conversion on sales.
We're trying to be really specific on where the AI is going to add value.
In this case, it'll tag images or it'll search for
images with the right qualities thus making image search a lot more efficient.
We also have a clear set of data that's needed,
stocked images tagged with aesthetic qualities that are visually
aligned to one another and data that
specifies how similar one set of images is to another.
From a scope perspective as well,
this is when the user needs to find a stock photo for marketing collateral,
you'll want to select the best option based on
all variables to improve that conversion rate.
How do we measure success?
This is when users need to find the best stock image quickly.
This can also probably be expanded on in our metrics section quickly,
could be within 30 seconds, within five minutes.
What metrics specifically from
a business outcome are you going to use to measure success?