So often an e-commerce Company will come and say,
"hey I just want to improve sight conversion and I
want to use Machine Learning to do that."
High level business executives get super excited about this,
but breaking it down into a narrow and specific problem is critical for success.
So what that often results into is improving search results.
Improving search results really means improving the
click-through on the top 10 search results returned
which in particular cases could be around
improving the percent of Hero Images which feature the actual product.
So Home Depot had this problem and what they found
was that when a search result had a product image which was shown by
itself against a white background that converted a lot higher than what they call
lifestyle images which were products that were shown in
the context of a room with a lot of their furniture.
So they had this huge image database and there
were no tags on image database to distinguish for
the software developers which image to show if there were
five or six images per product which ones do they show in the search results.
They needed to tag all of these images and delineate
between these two different styles.
So this breaks down into a pretty simple image classification problem saying,
"hey, what type of image is this?
Is this a product image or is it
a lifestyle image or is it something else in my data that I'm not aware of?"
So I went to search for new towel bar the other day and
I could not find a search result that did not have
a product hero image featuring that where
should have been in the search results
and the lifestyle images were all correctly placed in a different section.
I searched long and hard to see if there were any that were out of
place and it looks like they really nailed this using machine-learning.
Switching gears a little bit,
say you're a large retailer.
This is a company that works with retailers Bossanova
and they deploy robots that
go up and down the aisles and figure out what
is out of stock to help improve the store experience.
So really the business problem here that they're solving for is improving
the customer experience and improving repeat customer business of that store.
So to improve that store experience it's really about
making sure the percent of shelves are fully stocked.
If you've ever gone into
a grocery store and things are out of stock, it's super annoying.
I don't want to go to another grocery store.
That means you need to understand which products specifically are
understaffed and delineate from a computer vision perspective between
what a stock shelf look like and what an empty shelf look like and
also an OCR task around identifying exactly what product is
missing from that shelf.
Visually it could look like this.
From the point of view of the robot going up and down the store,
they need to identify, "hey,
this is a full shelf or this is an empty shell."
If it's empty here's what product is supposed to be there
and visually transcribing
what that is and sending that information to
the store associates to go restock that shelf.
Alternatively, I've seen a lot of Machine Learning Projects stumble or
fail or not go anywhere interesting
because they aren't clear enough on the business problem.
Take for example, a fashion retailer who started with the data
they had which was lots of
imagery from fashion over the last 15 years and they wanted to
classify at all to understand what was in that whole image set.
However, simply classifying all the different fashion types
didn't really lead them to any valuable business outcome.
Besides a very loosely tag data-set of shirts and pants and purses.
It wasn't particularly meaningful.
Of course it's all fashion catalog because that's all the data that they have.
None of the business leader has got any value from this project.
In summary here, you want to make sure that you are deploying for
a very targeted narrow and specific use case
that is measurable with business outcomes.
You want to put the business problem before the data.
It's almost always better to start with a business case and
evaluate options for how to achieve success in that special case,
sometimes it's a Machine Learning problem, sometimes it's not.
Success depends on the data.
Our AI systems are only as good as the data that we put into them.
If your data is bad, your Machine Learning tools are useless.