So you may not be able to train your model on all the possible data points.
In our case, it was pretty simple.
It was a yes/no. But you will sometimes need to design for unknown cases.
In terms of a job design,
this could be handled by including an unknown or
an unable to answer option among the labels.
You should design for the outcome with the least negative impact.
So if we take a look at this sign over here,
this would be safest to say that this is a no parking sign.
We want to decrease the chances of someone getting
a parking ticket and because this is such a confusing image,
it is best to say no parking
regardless of whether there are
three hours in the day that you might be able to park there.