So real continuous data also changes all the time.
So how can you plan for long-term success?
If your dataset absolutely does not change,
then you can use a static model which is trained once
and used indefinitely until an update is required.
But if your data is ever evolving as many are,
you should use a dynamic model which is continuously trained on new data,
so it can keep learning from new input.
If your data does change frequently,
you may need to continue making changes to
your annotation job to reflect more relevant definitions or examples.
For example, if you built a clothing classifier,
imagine you trained it on pants, tops,
and dresses, but now you've started including jumpsuits in your dataset.
In each train the model on this new data point to
avoid jumpsuits being labeled as pants or dresses.
Or if your model is region-based and you want to expand,
you'll need to train it on entirely new data altogether.
For example, if we wanted to expand our San Francisco parking sign dataset into London,
we'd need to train it all signs around London because they're
completely different from those seen in San Francisco.