You've learned a lot in this lesson and I wanted to do a quick recap.
First, we talked about how the data really
defines what patterns in machine learning model can learn.
So how complete the data is,
and how well it fits your business use case can really affect the accuracy of the model.
Then we talked about methods for creating a dataset and annotating existing data.
Specifically, how you can design a data annotation job that includes
clear instructions for human annotators and examples of each datatype.
Finally, something to keep in mind is updating your model
as needed in response to changes in the underlying data.
You should always keep your user front of mind and
consider how you might improve the model over time.
This information is really useful for a variety of products,
and the ability to create a new data set is something
you'll need if you're creating a new product or application.
Next you'll get a chance to apply what you've learned in a data annotation project.