How model performs depends heavily on the training data you give it.
So say you have a business problem,
how can you use data to best set up a model for success?
One thing to think about is do you have enough data?
Many machine-learning algorithms need many examples of every different type of
data to be able to learn to distinguish between different classes and find patterns.
Imagine your aim is to train a machine learning model to
distinguish between positive and negative movie reviews.
You'll need a lot of review data to be able to find
the specific words or phrases that can help you categorize any new review.
Just a few data points will not provide enough information,
it will build some bias and inaccuracy in your resulted model.
More data gives a machine-learning algorithm more context and information to learn from.
A good data set that has many examples of the different classes of data.
In this case negative and positive movie reviews,
will help them model generalize better when faced with new user data.