In order to train your model,
you'll need annotated data.
Whether that means categorizing text,
outlining objects and images,
or any number of labeling requirements.
For this, you might choose a data labeling platform like Figure Eight.
This requires a few steps,
uploading data, designing a job,
creating test questions, launching and monitoring results,
and we'll go over each of these steps in more detail soon.
It's easiest to learn these steps in an example,
and I'll show you how we at Figure Eight annotated a dataset of parking sign images.
Here's what an image from this dataset looks like.
These are images taken around San Francisco,
and the aim of this project was to identify the signs
as distinct from the background and other objects.
A later project may be able to actually read and
identify the different types of signs, but for now,
we want to take a bunch of images from around San Francisco and label them as containing,
or not containing a sign.
A yes/no label. Next, I'll go over designing a data annotation job generally,
and then using this parking sign data.