So when you go to the figure eight platform,
you'll be taken to our template library,
where all of our use cases are broken down
such as sentiment analysis, search relevance etc.
We're going to go into image annotation and in here,
we have several different job types mostly tailored to actually annotating images.
So placing bounding boxes around items,
using polygon tools outline objects etc.
We'll go down to the image categorization.
So we can preview this template in the platform
here and we can see that there's a set of instructions.
In this case, we're categorizing whether an image includes animals.
What kind of animal it is and if there is another type of animal what that would be.
So we have examples,
how they should be categorized,
and then further down,
we can see the job design itself.
This is interactive.
So we can click each of
the options and see all the different types of elements that pop up.
So we know that this will work for our use case.
Let's go ahead and use this template.