So we're taken into the data page,
which is where we'll upload our source data.
While this is uploading, you'll see a little message in
the bottom that tells you how many units have been uploaded.
We can go ahead and start designing while we wait for the data to be imported.
So our column mapper allows us to pretty quickly
map our source data to the existing job designs.
So our image URL is already mapped in. This is perfect.
We can see this job has a lot going on in this design.
So this is built in CML,
which stands for Custom Markup Language,
which is an HTML based language.
It's just specific to figure eight.
So CML is basically creating the elements that your contributors,
so the people working in your job will see.
So if we go down and take a look at preview,
we can see that our CML for radio has created a radio element.
Because I mapped our data into this job,
our new San Francisco data is showing here instead of animal images.
So, I'm going to go into a job that was already run using the Parking Sign Data.
If we go to this design page,
we can see the design is much simpler,
because we're only asking one question.
So we'll take a look at the preview for this.